<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
		"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<chapter id="using-snaps">
	<title>Using @snaps.product.name@ in your application</title>
	<para>
		Every snap or host should also be a regular WAB (Web Application Bundle), all you have to do is add some additional 
		configuration to benefit from @snaps.product.name.short@.
	</para>
	
	<section id="using-snaps-configuring-the-host">
		<title>Configuring the Host</title>
		<para>
			In the WAB that is to act as a host to Snaps bundles, all that needs to be added is a filter in the hosts '
			<literal>web.xml</literal>'. This filter can be mapped to any sub path that you want forwarded to registered 
			snaps. It is important to note the extra <literal>dispatcher</literal> declarations in the <literal>filter-mapping</literal>. 
			Without these internal lookups, resources like JSPs won't get passed to the appropriate snap when needed.
		</para>
		<programlisting>
<![CDATA[<filter>
    <filter-name>host-filter-name</filter-name>
    <filter-class>org.eclipse.virgo.snaps.core.SnapHostFilter</filter-class>
</filter>

<filter-mapping>
    <filter-name>host-filter-name</filter-name>
    <url-pattern>/*</url-pattern>
    <dispatcher>INCLUDE</dispatcher>
    <dispatcher>FORWARD</dispatcher>
    <dispatcher>REQUEST</dispatcher>
</filter-mapping>]]>
		</programlisting>
	</section>
	
	<section id="using-snaps-configuring-a-snap">
		<title>Configuring a Snap</title>
		<para>
			A snap is a normal WAB with the addition of two extra manifest headers. The first <literal>Snap-Host</literal> is used 
			to resolve the WAB you want to act as a host for this snap. The second <literal>Snap-ContextPath</literal> gives the 
			path the snap will answer to. In order to reach the snap a request must be made for the host's context path, plus any 
			path in the host's Snaps filter followed by the path given with the <literal>Snap-ContextPath</literal> header.
		</para>
		<programlisting>
<![CDATA[Snap-Host: org.eclipse.virgo.snaps.sample.animal;version="${version:[=.=.=, =.+1)}"
Snap-ContextPath: /dog]]>
		</programlisting>
	</section>
	
	<section id="using-snaps-taglibs">
		<title>Using the Snaps taglibs</title>
		<para>
			There is a tag library available that makes information about the Snaps environment available to the host from within a 
			JSP page. The prefix and URI to declare are <code>&#60;%@ taglib prefix="snaps" uri="http://www.eclipse.org/virgo/snaps" 
			%&#62;</code>. You can now access an array of all the Snaps currently registered with the host. Each snap in the array
			has two values, the first is the context path the Snap is registered with, as given in the snaps manifest header. The 
			second is an array of properties, if any, given in a property file in the snap. The file must be in the <literal>META-INF
			</literal> directory and have a name of <literal>snap.properties</literal>. The following code snippet shows all of these 
			in use to produce links to each of the installed snaps.
		</para>
		<programlisting>
<![CDATA[<snaps:snaps var="snaps">
    <c:forEach var="snap" items="${snaps}">
        <a href="<c:url value="${snap.contextPath}${snap.properties['link.path']}"/>">
                     ${snap.properties['link.text']}</a>
    </c:forEach>
</snaps:snaps>]]>
		</programlisting>
		<para>
			The first line uses the Snaps tag library to place the array of snaps into the <code>snaps</code> variable. Then a 
			<code>forEach</code> loop goes through each snap. The content of the <code>forEach</code> loop is the really interesting 
			bit. The first variable <code>${snap.contextPath}</code> returns the context path of the snap. The two lookups are for 
			properties <code>${snap.properties['something']}</code>. They rely on the snap having the properties file in place with 
			<literal>link.path</literal> and <literal>link.text</literal> defined in it. This shows the flexibility you have for defining 
			your own contract between the host and its snaps. In this case each snap can contribute extra information about how links in 
			a menu should be constructed.
		</para>
	</section>
	
	<section id="using-snaps-host-prefix">
		<title>Referencing Resources</title>
		<para>
			If the snap needs to lookup any resources, this can be done in the normal way and if the resource cannot be found in the snap, 
			then the host will be checked. Remember that a host and all its snaps use a single <literal>ServletContext</literal>. As the 
			snap is always checked first it can hide resources at the same path in its host. So if you want to look up a resource in the 
			snaps host that exists in the snap simply prefix the path with <code>host:</code>. This will then cause the Snaps system to 
			bypass the snap and look only in its host for the requested resource. If it is not found in its host the snap will NOT be 
			checked, the lookup will return with nothing.
			<programlisting>
<![CDATA[request.getServletContext().getResource("host:/WEB-INF/sample.properties");]]>
			</programlisting>
			<para>
				This line of Java code gets the ServletContext from the HttpRequest object and then tries to get a resource from the host, 
				bypassing the snap.
			</para>
		</para>
	</section>
	
</chapter>